A Guide to the Henry Luce Foundation records, Record Group 4, Accession 2017:060 FA1442
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Project Files, 1990-2014; 1
  - Maria Mitchell Association - Support for the Women in Science Award, 2005-2011 (Box 37, Folder 239)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Terrascope Program Field Research, 2004-2010 (Box 37, Folder 240)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Terrascope Program Field Research - TerraRadio Program Broadcast on WMBR-FM, 2005 May 12 (Box 37, Folder 240)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Terrascope Program Field Research - Terrascope Recruitment Video, 2006 (Box 37, Folder 240)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Terrascope Program Field Research - TerraRadio Chile (Box 37, Folder 240)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Terrascope Program Field Research - Terrascope Short Intro, 2005 March 3 (Box 37, Folder 240)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Terrascope Program Field Research - Terrascope the Video, 2005 March 3 (Box 37, Folder 240)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Visualizing Cultures Project, 2008-2010 (Box 37, Folder 241)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, List Visual Arts Center - Publication of Interpretive Materials about the American Art Installed throughout Campus, 2008-2011 (Box 37, Folder 242)
  - Massachusetts Museum of Contemporary Art - Documentation and Interpretive Elements of a Long-Term Sol LeWitt Installation, 2008-2009 (Box 38, Folder 243)
  - Maysles Institute - Tibet in Harlem 2 Film, 2010 (Box 38, Folder 244)
  - Mead Art Museum, Amherst College - Thomas Cole Frame Restoration, 2011 (Box 38, Folder 245)
  - MEM Associates, Inc. - Arts and Religion Project, 1995-2002 (Box 38, Folder 246-248)
  - Memorial Art Gallery, University of Rochester - George Bellows at Woodstock, 1920-1924, 2001-2014 (Box 39, Folder 249)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art - American Stories: Paintings of Everyday Life, 1765-1915, 2007-2010 (Box 39, Folder 250)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Reinstallation of American Paintings, 2011-2012 (Box 39, Folder 251)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Update the Henry R. Luce Center for the Study of American Art, 2008-2012 (Box 39, Folder 252)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art - The World of Khubilai Khan: Chinese Art in the Yuan Dynasty, 2010-2011 (Box 39, Folder 253)
  - Mint Museum of Art - Copley Frame Restoration, 2009-2010 (Box 39, Folder 254)
  - Montclair Art Museum - Cezanne and American Modernism, 2007-2010 (Box 40, Folder 255-256)
  - Montgomery Museum of Fine Arts - Staffing and Programming (American Art Renewal Fund), 2010-2011 (Box 40, Folder 257)
  - Monterey Museum of Art - West to East: Retracing the Path of Abstraction, 2008-2011 (Box 40, Folder 258)
  - Morehouse School of Medicine - Humanities in Medicine Program, 1992-1995 (Box 40, Folder 259)
  - Museum of Contemporary Art, Chicago - Jim Nutt: Coming into Character, 2006-2011 (Box 40, Folder 260)
  - Museum of Contemporary Art, San Diego - American Art Collection Awareness, 1996-2004 (Box 41, Folder 261-262)
  - Museum of Contemporary Art, San Diego - Phenomenal: California Light and Space, 2008-2012 (Box 41, Folder 263)
  - Museum of Contemporary Art, San Diego - Phenomenal: California Light and Space - Untitled CD (Box 41, Folder 263)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston - Learning Gallery Interpreting the American Art Collection, 2006-2011 (Box 41, Folder 264-265)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston - Reinstall American Art Collection in the American Wing, 2009-2011 (Box 41, Folder 266)
  - National Academy Museum - George Tooker: A Retrospective, 2007-2010 (Box 42, Folder 267)
  - National Academy Museum - Reinstall the American Art Collection, 2011-2012 (Box 42, Folder 268)
  - National Bureau of Asian Research - Seminar for University Leaders on Asian Policy Issues (Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars), 2008-2012 (Box 42, Folder 269)
  - National Bureau of Asian Research - United States-Thailand Research Project, 2011-2012 (Box 42, Folder 270)
  - National Committee on American Foreign Policy - Policy Dialogues on Northeast Asia Security Issues, 2007-2011 (Box 42, Folder 271-272)
  - National Committee on American Foreign Policy - Policy Dialogues on Northeast Asia Security Issues (Renewal), 2010-2012 (Box 42, Folder 273)
  - National Committee on United States-China Relations - New Generation of China Policy Specialists (Public Intellectuals Program), 2004-2012 (Box 43, Folder 274)
  - National Fund for the United States Botanic Garden - National Garden on the National Mall, Washington, D.C., 1992-2010 (Box 43, Folder 275)
  - National Museum of the American Indian - Infinity Nations Exhibit, 2004-2011 (Box 43, Folder 276)
  - National Taiwan University - Regional Study on Democracy and Governance in Asia (Asian Barometer Survey), 2005-2012 (Box 43, Folder 277)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation - Hurricane Katrina Recovery Work, 2007-2008 (Box 43, Folder 278)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation - Modernism and Recent Past: Initiative to Preserve 20th Century American Architecture, 2008-2011 (Box 44, Folder 279)
  - New Britain Museum of American Art - The World of Charles Ethan Porter: 19th Century African American Artis, 2006-2010 (Box 44, Folder 280)
  - New Britain Museum of American Art - John Haberle: Master of Illusion, 2009-2010 (Box 44, Folder 281)
  - New England Foundation for the Arts - Voices from the Shadows: Multimedia Project on Women and Religion in Pakistan, 2010-2011 (Box 44, Folder 282-283)
  - New Museum of Contemporary Art - Digital Archive of Museum's History and Programs, 2008-2010 (Box 44, Folder 284)
  - RAND Corporation - Gulf States Policy Institute, 2006-2010 (Box 45, Folder 285)
  - Redwood Library and Athenaeum - Preservation of American Paintings, 2001-2010 (Box 45, Folder 286)
  - Rice University - Consumer Citizenship: Marketing in Civil Society, 2001-2011 (Box 45, Folder 287-288)
  - Rochester Institute of Technology - Doctorate Program in Sustainability, 2006-2011 (Box 45, Folder 289)
  - Norman Rockwell Museum - Project NORMAN (Electronic Art and Archives Management Network), 2004-2010 (Box 46, Folder 290)
  - Norman Rockwell Museum - Representation of American Museums at the United States-Russia Bilateral Presidential Commission (Laurie Norton Moffatt), 2009 (Box 46, Folder 291)
  - Norman Rockwell Museum - Lend "The Problem We All Live With" to the White House, 2011 (Box 46, Folder 292)
  - Millicent Rogers Museum - Southwest Native American Jewelry Collection (American Collections Enhancement Initiative), 1998-2011 (Box 46, Folder 293-294)
  - Millicent Rogers Museum - Debt Reduction (American Art Renewal Fund), 2010-2011 (Box 46, Folder 295)
  - Rose Art Museum - Visiting Scholars Program in Contemporary Art (American Collections Enhancement Initiative), 2000-2011 (Box 46, Folder 296)
  - American Associates of the Royal Academy Trust - Luce Annual Lecture on American Creativity, 2000-2011 (Box 47, Folder 297-298)
  - San Antonio Museum of Art - Upgrade the American Art Collection Storage Facilities, 2007-2008 (Box 47, Folder 299)
  - Seattle Art Museum - Coast Salish Art and Artists: S'ABADEB (The Gifts), 2002-2010 (Box 47, Folder 300)
  - Seattle Art Museum - Native American Curator and American Art Insurance Fund (American Art Renewal Fund), 2010-2011 (Box 47, Folder 301)
  - Seventh Regiment Armory Conservancy, Inc. - Cataloging and Assessment of American Fine and Decorative Art Collection, 2008-2010 (Box 47, Folder 302)
  - Shelburne Museum - American Art Staff Positions (American Art Renewal Fund), 2011-2012 (Box 48, Folder 303)
  - Sheldon Memorial Art Gallery, University of Nebraska - The Unknown Blakelock, 2006-2010 (Box 48, Folder 304)
  - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture - Preserve and Disseminate Lecture Archive, 2001-2010 (Box 48, Folder 305)
  - Smithsonian American Art Museum - Joseph Cornell: Navigating the Imagination, 2003-2010 (Box 48, Folder 306)
  - Smithsonian Institution - Southeast Asia Initiatives at the Freer Gallery of Art and Arthur M. Sackler Gallery, 2010-2012 (Box 48, Folder 307-308)
  - Social Science Research Council - Religion and International Affairs: Strengthening Scholarly and Public Attention, 2005-2011 (Box 49, Folder 309)
  - Society for the Preservation of Long Island Antiquities - Digitization Project, 2000-2010 (Box 49, Folder 310)
  - Society of Women Engineers - Women in Engineering Leadership Institute (WELI) Workshop, 2005-2011 (Box 49, Folder 311)
  - Spencer Museum of Art, University of Kansas - Aaron Douglas: African American Modernist, 2003-2010 (Box 49, Folder 312)
  - Spencer Museum of Art, University of Kansas - Aaron Douglas and the Harlem Renaissance, 2007-2010 (Box 49, Folder 313)
  - Stanford University - Forum for American/Chinese Exchange at Stanford (FACES), 2005-2011 (Box 49, Folder 314)
  - Syracuse University - Visual Art Journalist Residency, 2009-2011 (Box 49, Folder 315)
  - Tacoma Art Museum - Cecilia Beaux: American Figure Painter, 2007-2010 (Box 50, Folder 316)
  - Telfair Museum of Art - Dutch Utopia: American Artists in Holland, 1880-1914, 2008-2011 (Box 50, Folder 317-318)
  - Tibet House - Marion Griebenow Photograph Archive, 1993-2010 (Box 50, Folder 319)
  - Toledo Museum of Art - American Art Research, Exhibitions, Publications, Public Programs (American Art Renewal Fund), 2011-2012 (Box 50, Folder 320)
  - United Nations Association - Chinese-American Dialogue on the United Nations, 1994-1999 (Box 50, Folder 321-322)
  - United Theological Seminary of the Twin Cities - Religion and the Arts Planning Grant, 1994-1995 (Box 51, Folder 323)
  - University Art Museum, University of California, Santa Barbara - Carefree California: Cliff May and the Romance of the Ranch, 2008-2012 (Box 51, Folder 324)
  - University at Buffalo, Art Gallery - Artpark, 1974-1984, 2009-2011 (Box 51, Folder 325)
  - University of California, Berkeley - Over a Hundred Years of Collecting: The History of East Asian Collection in the United States, 2006-2012 (Box 51, Folder 326)
  - University of California, Los Angeles - "Steeped in History: The Art of Tea" and "Weavers' Stories from Island Southeast Asia" Exhibits, 2009-2012 (Box 51, Folder 327-328)
  - University of California, Los Angeles - "Steeped in History: The Art of Tea" and "Weavers' Stories from Island of Southeast Asia" Exhibits - In Their Own Words, By Their Own Hands, Fowler Museum at UCLA, Sisilia Sii, Island of Flores (Box 51, Folder 327-328)
  - University of California, Los Angeles - "Steeped in History: The Art of Tea" and "Weavers' Stories from Island of Southeast Asia" Exhibits - Intersections: World Arts, Local Lives - Kiosk Video, "Sisilia Sii: Weaver" Fowler Museum at UCLA (Box 51, Folder 327-328)
  - University of Chicago - Early Chinese Excavated Texts, 2007-2012 (Box 52, Folder 329)
  - University of Denver - China Program at the Graduate School of International Studies, 2000-2012 (Box 52, Folder 330)
  - University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign - Film Screenings by the Asian Educational Media Service (AEMS) at the 2011 Meeting of the Association of Asian Studies (AAS), 2010-2011 (Box 52, Folder 331)
  - University of Maine - Vietnam Oral History Project, 2008-2011 (Box 52, Folder 332)
  - University of Maryland - New Critical Perspectives on African American History, National Art History Conference 2008, 2007-2010 (Box 52, Folder 333)
  - University of Maryland - Visual Culture of American Religions, 1995-2000 (Box 52, Folder 334)
  - University of Michigan - Multiple Impressions: Contemporary Chinese Woodblock Prints, 2011-2012 (Box 53, Folder 335-336)
  - University of Michigan - Women's Studies Graduate Program with Fudan University, 2005-2010 (Box 53, Folder 337-338)
  - University of Michigan, Center for Southeast Asian Studies - International Conference on Southeast Asian Studies: Looking Back and Looking Ahead, 2010-2012 (Box 53, Folder 339)
  - University of Pennsylvania - Faculty and Curriculum Development Seminar in Japan, 2004-2010 (Box 53, Folder 340)
  - University of Southern California - Religion, Identity and Global Governance, 2006-2011 (Box 54, Folder 341)
  - University of Virginia - Traditions of Exemplary Women (Digital Resource on Women and Culture in Early China), 2003-2012 (Box 54, Folder 342-343)
  - University of Washington - Environmental Management Keystone Projects, 2005-2010 (Box 54, Folder 344)
  - University of Washington - Environmental Management Keystone Projects - The Business Case for Sustainability, I. Hunter Lovins, UWTV Productions, 2006 November 8 (Box 54, Folder 344)
  - University of Washington - Environmental Management Keystone Projects - University of Washington Program for the Environment Presents: Dr. Richard Sandor, Chairman and Founder, Chicago Climate Change, 2007 May 1 (Box 54, Folder 344)
  - University of Washington - Environmental Management Keystone Projects - Alan Durning Lecture, UW Kane Hall, 2007 February 28 (Box 54, Folder 344)
  - University of Washington, ADVANCE Center for Institutional Change - Interrupting Bias in the Faculty Search Process: A Film and Facilitation Guide, 2009-2012 (Box 54, Folder 345)
  - University of Washington, ADVANCE Center for Institutional Change - Interrupting Bias in the Faculty Search Process: A Film and Facilitation Guide (Box 54, Folder 345)
  - Utah Museum of Fine Arts, University of Utah - American Art: Challenging Traditional Interpretations, Selections for the Permanent Collection Catalog (American Collections Enhancement), 1999-2004 (Box 54, Folder 346)
  - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts - James McNeill Whistler, 1990-2005 (Box 55, Folder 347-348)
  - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts - Reinterpret and Reinstall the American Art Collection, 2008-2010 (Box 55, Folder 349-350)
  - Volunteers in Asia - Expanded Southeast Asia Program, 2007-2011 (Box 55, Folder 351)
  - Walker Art Center - Hire a Senior Curator (American Art Renewal Fund), 2011-2012 (Box 55, Folder 352)
  - Walker Art Center - Survey the Print Collection, 2009-2010 (Box 55, Folder 353)
  - Weatherspoon Art Museum - "70 Years of Collecting" Collection Handbook, 2008-2011 (Box 56, Folder 354)
  - Women in Engineering ProActive Network (WEPAN) - Promote Women in Engineering, 2004-2011 (Box 56, Folder 355)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art - Gordon Matta-Clark, 2006-2010 (Box 56, Folder 356)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art - "Landscape and Industry" and "Flashpoints: The Whitney's Collection at 75" Exhibits, 2005-2010 (Box 56, Folder 357)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art - Lyonel Feininger: At the Edge of the World, 2010-2012 (Box 56, Folder 358)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art - Phase I of the Collection and Documentation Initiative, 2008-2010 (Box 56, Folder 359)
  - Williams College Museum of Art - Curatorial Sabbatical for Nancy Mowll Mathews, 2005-2012 (Box 56, Folder 360)
  - Wilson College - Global Citizenship Initiative, 2009-2010 (Box 56, Folder 361)
  - Winterthur Museum and Country Estate - Paint, Pattern and People: Furniture of Southeastern Pennsylvania, 1725-1850, 2007-2012 (Box 57, Folder 362-363)
  - Wolfsonian-Florida International University - Creator, Collector, Catalyst: The University Art Museum in the 21st Century, 2006-2010 (Box 57, Folder 364)
  - Woodrow Wilson Center - Cold War International History Project, China Initiative, 2003-2010 (Box 57, Folder 365-366)
  - Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars - "Human Rights: Challenges of the Past and Challenges of the Future" Conference, 2008-2010 (Box 57, Folder 367)
  - Woods Hold Research Center - Competing Human Uses for Land, Soils and Vegetation in a Climate-Challenged World, 2006-2010 (Box 58, Folder 368)
  - Yellowstone Art Museum - Dedicated Gallery for Permanent American Art Collection, 2007-2012 (Box 58, Folder 369-370)
  - Henry Luce Foundation Staff Chrons, 2005 (Box 58, Folder 371-373, Box 59, Folder 374-378, Box 60, Folder 379-384, Box 61, Folder 385-387)
- American Art Conservation Initiative Files, 2006-2014; 2
  Biographical / Historical
  The American Art Conservation Initiative was a one-year program which funded the conservation of art in United States museums. These grants covered the cost of ongoing conservation treatments, such as exhibition preparation, stabilization, and framing. Eligible media included paintings, sculptures, drawings, prints, decorative arts, textiles, and photography.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by institution.
  - Conservation Initiative Information, 2007 (Box 61, Folder 388)
  - Albright-Knox Art Gallery - Conserve American Paintings for National Exhibition Tour, 2007-2009 (Box 61, Folder 389)
  - American Textile History Museum - Conserve Historic American Textiles and Costumes for an Oriental Exhibition, 2007-2009 (Box 61, Folder 390)
  - Art Institute of Chicago - Treatment of 19th Century American Frames and Early 20th Century American Furniture, 2007-2011 (Box 61, Folder 391)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art - Treatment of Frames for Early American Paintings, 2007-2011 (Box 61, Folder 392)
  - Barnes Foundation - Conserve and Stabilize 19th Century Native American Ceramics, 2007-2010 (Box 61, Folder 393)
  - Bowdoin College Museum of Art - Treatment and Reframing of American Paintings for the Reinstallation of the Permanent Collection, 2007-2008 (Box 61, Folder 394)
  - Brookgreen Gardens - Conservation of American Sculptures, 2007-2008 (Box 62, Folder 395)
  - Buffalo Bill Historical Center - Conservation of Outdoor American Sculpture, 2007-2008 (Box 62, Folder 396)
  - Butler Institute of American Art - Restore Paintings from the Original Collection, 2007-2008 (Box 62, Folder 397)
  - Carnegie Museum of Art - Conserve a Suite of American Late-Neoclassical Period Furniture for Permanent Installation in the New Decorative Arts Area, 2007-2009 (Box 62, Folder 398)
  - Chinati Foundation - Conserve Signature Outdoor Sculpture by Donald Judd, 2007-2009 (Box 62, Folder 399)
  - Cleveland Museum of Art - Conserve American Modernist Sculpture during the Museum's Capital Expansion Project, 2007-2011 (Box 62, Folder 400)
  - Cliveden of the National Trust - Conserve a Portrait of Anne Thompson by Julian Russel Story, 2007-2008 (Box 62, Folder 401)
  - Corcoran Museum of Art - Conservation of the Period Frame for "The Last Buffalo" Painting by Albert Bierstadt, 2007-2008 (Box 62, Folder 402)
  - Cummer Museum of Art and Gardens - Conserve American Bronze Sculpture "Diana of the Hunt", 2007-2009 (Box 62, Folder 403)
  - Delaware Art Museum - Restore John Sloan Works, 2007-2010 (Box 62, Folder 404)
  - Denver Art Museum - Conserve Navajo Textiles, 2007-2011 (Box 62, Folder 405)
  - Grand Rapids Art Museum - Refurbish Frames for American Paintings, 2007-2008 (Box 62, Folder 406)
  - Hunter Museum of American Art - Conserve Period Frames for American 19th Century Paintings, 2007-2011 (Box 63, Folder 407)
  - The Jewish Museum - Conserve Vintage American Photographs, 2007-2009 (Box 63, Folder 408)
  - List Visual Arts Center, Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Conserve "Here-There" Mural by Kenneth Noland, 2007-2009 (Box 63, Folder 409)
  - Memorial Art Gallery, University of Rochester - Long-Term Storage of American Paintings, 2007-2011 (Box 63, Folder 410)
  - Munson Williams Proctor Arts Institute - Conservation of American Paintings and Works on Paper for a Travelling Exhibit, 2007-2009 (Box 63, Folder 411)
  - Museum of Arts and Design - Restoration of "Alice House Wall" by Robert Arneson, 2007-2010 (Box 63, Folder 412)
  - Museum of Contemporary Art, San Diego - Conserve "Untitled" by California Artist Ed Moses, 2007-2014 (Box 63, Folder 413)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston - Conserve American Paintings and Furniture for Reinstallation in New American Art Wing, 2007-2010 (Box 63, Folder 414)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Houston - Conserve Key American Neoclassical Furniture Displayed in the Bayou Bend House, 2007-2009 (Box 63, Folder 415)
  - Museum of Indian Arts and Culture - Conservation of Pueblo Pottery, 2007-2011 (Box 63, Folder 416)
  - Museum of Modern Art - Conservator to Refurbish Edward Hopper Paintings, 2007-2010 (Box 64, Folder 417)
  - National Museum of the American Indian - Conserve Works for a New Permanent Collection at the Heye Center Branch in New York City, 2007-2010 (Box 64, Folder 418)
  - New Britain Museum - Conserve American Paintings, 2007-2011 (Box 64, Folder 419)
  - Newark Museum - Conserve Paintings for a National Travelling Exhibition, 2007-2008 (Box 64, Folder 420)
  - North Carolina Museum of Art - Conserve 20th Century Works in Preparation for Installation in New American Art Galleries, 2007-2009 (Box 64, Folder 421)
  - Oakland Museum of California - Conserve Paintings for Installation in the New Gallery of California Art, 2007-2009 (Box 64, Folder 422)
  - Georgia O'Keeffe Museum - Conserve Recently Acquired Works Inadequately Stored in the Artist's Home, 2007-2011 (Box 64, Folder 423)
  - Parrish Art Museum - Conserve American Paintings in Preparation for Installation in the Museum's New Building, 2007-2012 (Box 64, Folder 424)
  - Peabody Essex Museum - Conserve Historic American Wedding Garments for Exhibition, 2007-2008 (Box 64, Folder 425)
  - Philadelphia Museum of Art - Conserve American Paintings for Installation in New American Galleries, 2007-2011 (Box 64, Folder 426)
  - The Phillips Collection - Conservation of Brett Weston Photographs in Preparation for a Touring Exhibit, 2007-2011 (Box 65, Folder 427)
  - Reynolda House Museum - Conservation of "Piece" (Charles Sheeler), "Two Dances" (Max Weber), "Spring Turning" (Grant Wood), and "The Storm (George Inness), 2007-2011 (Box 65, Folder 428)
  - Seattle Art Museum - Period Frames for Paintings by John Singleton Copley and Rembrandt Peale, 2007 (Box 65, Folder 429)
  - Clyfford Still Museum - Conserve Paintings from Still's Personal Collection for their First Public Exhibition (Box 65, Folder 430)
  - Toledo Museum of Art - Conserve "2 Circle IV" Sculpture by David Smith, 2007-2009 (Box 65, Folder 431)
  - Wadsworth Atheneum Museum of Art - Conserve American Drawings in Preparation for an Exhibition and Catalog, 2007-2009 (Box 65, Folder 432)
  - Walters Art Museum - Conserve Original Frames for Alfred Jacob Miller Paintings, 2007-2011 (Box 65, Folder 433)
  - Warner House Association - Restore "In Situ" Ceiling Paintings by Nehemiah Partridge, 2007-2008 (Box 65, Folder 434)
  - Washington Art Consortium - Conservation of American Works on Paper, 2007-2009 (Box 65, Folder 435)
  - Frank Lloyd Wright Preservation Trust - Conservation of Furniture Designed by Frank Lloyd Wright for his Home in Oak Park, 2007-2008 (Box 65, Folder 436)
- Luce Fund for Southeast Asian Studies, 1982-2005; 3
  The Luce Fund for Southeast Asian Studies was designed to enhance the quality of Southeast Asian studies at both the graduate and the undergraduate levels at American Universities. It was a competitive grant program for universities that have made significant commitments to the field of Southeast Asian studies. Grants were awarded for faculty development, library development, student fellowships, public education, and other programs that were considered beneficial to the growth of the field.
  The Luce Fund for Southeast Asian Studies series contains general information about the initiative including program guidelines, grants, and surveys. This series also includes information about each of the nine institutions that were invited to participate in the program: Cornell University, Northern Illinois University, Northwest Regional Consortium for Southeast Asian Studies (Universities of Oregon and Washington), Ohio University, University of California (Berkeley), University of Hawaii, University of Michigan, University of Wisconsin (Madison), and Yale University.
  - Announcements, Articles, Press Releases, 1987 (Box 66, Folder 437)